[
  {
      "question": "When God spoke to Joshua about what they should do with regards to Jericho, How many priests were to move before the ark and what were they to carry?",
      "answer": "Joshua6:4, Seven priests, to carry/bear seven trumpets of ram’s horns."
  },
  {
      "question": "How many times all together were the children of Israel to go about the city of Jericho, give the total number of times and the breakdown of how they were to go about the city?",
      "answer": "Joshua6:3-4, 13 times, they were to go once for the first six days and seven times on the seventh day."
  },
  {
      "question": "Which king led a coalition against Joshua and the Israelites?",
      "answer": "Jabin, the king of Hazor (Joshua 11:1)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Where did the defeated kings and their cities come together to wage war against Joshua and Israel in Joshua 11?",
      "answer": "The defeated kings and their cities came together to wage war against Joshua and Israel in the region of the waters of Merom. (Joshua 11:5)"
  },
  {
      "question": "The family heads of the Levites approached three set of people in respect of cities to dwell in and common lands for their livestock. Mention their names",
      "answer": "Eleazar the priest, Joshua the son of Nun and other family heads of the tribes of Israel. Joshua 21:1."
  },
  {
      "question": "In which city did they search the scriptures daily to see if what Paul was teaching was true? ",
      "answer": "Berea (Acts 17:10-11)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Who accompanied Paul from Berea and joined him in Athens?",
      "answer": "Silas and Timotheus (Acts 17:15)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Who were the philosophers in Athens who encountered Paul and took him to Areopagus asking to know about the new doctrine?",
      "answer": "The certain philosophers were Epicureans and Stoics. (Acts 17:18)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Agrippa told Festus that Paul would have been set at liberty if he had not appealed unto __________?",
      "answer": "Caesar. Acts 26:32."
  },
  {
      "question": "Paul’s accusers had certain questions against him. Mention these two major areas?",
      "answer": "Their superstitions and the resurrection of Jesus Christ. Acts 25:19"
  },
  {
      "question": "Quote Acts 26:1.",
      "answer": "Then Agrippa said unto Paul, Thou art permitted to speak for thyself. Then Paul stretched forth the hand, and answered for himself. Acts 26:1."
  },
  {
      "question": "The first city was allotted to the __________Fill in the gap.",
      "answer": "Kohathites. Joshua 21:4"
  },
  {
      "question": "According to Joshua 1:4, God told Joshua that his territory will start from _______________ to _________________",
      "answer": "Lebanon to The Great Euphrates River"
  },
  {
      "question": "Quote Joshua 1:8",
      "answer": "This book of the law shall not depart out of thine mouth but thou shall meditate on it day and night that thou may observe to do according to all that is written therein, for then thou shall make thine way prosperous and thou shall have good success"
  },
  {
      "question": "__________ was the Great great grandfather of Zelophehad",
      "answer": "Manasseh Joshua 17:3a"
  },
  {
      "question": "According to Joshua 17:3b, a certain man had no sons but daughters, what was his name and how many Daughters did he have",
      "answer": "Zelophehad, 5 daughters."
  },
  {
      "question": "What did the church that was scattered abroad do when they were persecuted?",
      "answer": "Acts8:4. They went everywhere preaching the word."
  },
  {
      "question": "What were the names of the prophets and teachers in the church at Antioch?",
      "answer": "The prophets and teachers in the church at Antioch were Barnabas, Simeon called Niger, Lucius of Cyrene, Manaen. (Acts 13:1)"
  },
  {
      "question": "In which city did Paul and Barnabas encounter the false prophet named Bar-Jesus?",
      "answer": "They encountered Bar-Jesus in the city of Paphos. (Acts 13:6)"
  },
  {
      "question": "What was the name of the man that called for Barnabas and Paul and desired to hear the word of God?",
      "answer": "Sergius Paulus. (Acts 13:7)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Who was also known as Bar-Jesus and withstood Paul and Barnabas in Paphos?",
      "answer": "Elymas. (Acts 13:6 & 8)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Mention those who were saved in Jericho and why?",
      "answer": "Joshua 6:17, Rahab the harlot and all that are with her in the house, because she hid the messengers (spies) that we sent."
  },
  {
      "question": "What was Joshua’s warning to the people after he told them to shout for the Lord had given them the city?",
      "answer": "Joshua6:18-19, He said in any wise they should keep themselves from the accursed thing lest they make themselves accursed when they take from the accursed thing and make the camp of Israel a curse and trouble it, but all the silver, gold, vessels of brass and iron are consecrated to the Lord and shall come to his treasury."
  },
  {
      "question": "What was Joshua’s curse on Jericho after they had besieged it?",
      "answer": "Joshua6:26, Cursed be the man before the Lord that rises up to build it, he shall lay his foundation in his first born and in his youngest son shall he set up the gates of it."
  },
  {
      "question": "Who committed a trespass in the accursed thing, he was the great grandson of whom and of which tribe in Israel?",
      "answer": "Joshua7:1, Achan, the great grandson of Zerah, of the tribe of Judah."
  },
  {
      "question": "Which city did Joshua burn with fire?",
      "answer": "Hazor (Joshua 11:11, 13)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Apostle Paul while addressing the Elders at Ephesus, he spoke about two major content of his teachings, name them?",
      "answer": "Acts 20:21 Repentance towards God and Faith towards our Lord Jesus Christ."
  },
  {
      "question": "Saul was still breathing out threatenings and slaughter against the disciples of the Lord and went to the high priest for what?",
      "answer": "Acts9:2. He desired of him letters to Damascus to the synagogues that if he found any of them on his way whether men or women he might bring them bound unto Jerusalem."
  },
  {
      "question": "When Saul came near Damascus, suddenly a light shined round him and he heard a voice saying Saul, Saul, why persecutest thou me? Saul said who art thou lord? What was the Lord’s response to Saul?",
      "answer": "Acts9:5. The Lord said “I am Jesus whom thou persecutest: it is hard for thee to kick against the pricks"
  },
  {
      "question": "Saul was then brought into Damascus after his encounter with the Lord, and he was three days without ___________ and neither did ___________ nor _________.",
      "answer": "Acts9:9. Sight, Eat, Drink."
  },
  {
      "question": "The Lord instructed Ananias to go to the street called __________ and enquire in the house of ___________ for one called __________ of _________: for behold he prayeth.",
      "answer": "Acts9:11. Straight, Judas, Saul, Tarsus."
  },
  {
      "question": "What did God ask Joshua to do to the horses and chariots of the kings in Joshua 11?",
      "answer": "God asked him to hough their horses and burn their chariots with fire. (Joshua 11:6)"
  },
  {
      "question": "How many horses and chariots did Joshua capture from kingsin Joshua 11?",
      "answer": "Joshua captured all their horses and burned their chariots (Joshua 11:8b-9)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Which region did Joshua conquer and utterly destroy its kings in Joshua 11?",
      "answer": "Joshua conquered and utterly destroyed the region of the hill country, the south country, the valley, the slopes, and all their kings. (Joshua 11:16-17)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Who did Paul referred to as whited wall and why?",
      "answer": "The high priest, Ananias. Because despite being a custodian of the law, he doesn’t respect the law (An hypocrite).Yet he violated the law by commanding people standing close to Paul to smite him on the mouth. Acts 23:3."
  },
  {
      "question": "According to Acts 23, there was a dispute between the Pharisees and Sadducees. State the reason for this?",
      "answer": "Because the Sadducees say that there is no resurrection, neither angel nor spirit but the Pharisees confess both. Acts 23:7-8."
  },
  {
      "question": "Quote Acts 19:11.",
      "answer": "And God wrought special miracles by the hands of Paul."
  },
  {
      "question": "Which city did Philip go to preach Christ and who was the sorcerer there that believed the teachings of Philip?",
      "answer": "Acts8:5&13. The city of Samaria, Simon."
  },
  {
      "question": "Who did the apostles send to Samaria when they heard that they had received the word of God and why?",
      "answer": "Acts8:14-15, Peter and John, that they might receive the Holy Ghost."
  },
  {
      "question": "When Simon the sorcerer saw that through the laying on of hands of the Apostles, people received the Holy Ghost, what did he do?",
      "answer": "Acts8:18-19. He offered them money and said give me this power also that on whomsoever I lay hands, he may receive the Holy Ghost."
  },
  {
      "question": "Who did the angel of the Lord lead Philip to after the event at Samaria? Describe whom he was.",
      "answer": "Acts8:27. A man of Ethiopia, an eunuch of great authority under Candace queen of the Ethiopians, who had charge of all her treasure."
  },
  {
      "question": "How many people were involved in the conspiracy to kill Paul?",
      "answer": "More than forty people. Acts 23:13."
  },
  {
      "question": "How many cities were alloted to the children of Gershon?",
      "answer": "Thirteen (13). Joshua 21:6(b)."
  },
  {
      "question": "In how many days did Joshua tell the people they would cross Jordan.",
      "answer": "Three days (Joshua 1:11)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Name the tribes that had their inheritance on the east side of Jordan",
      "answer": "Reuben, Gad and Half the tribe of Manasseh (Joshua 1:12-15)"
  },
  {
      "question": "According to Joshua 1:18, the children of Israel agreed that anyone who didn’t obey the words of Joshua will ________________________",
      "answer": "Be put to death."
  },
  {
      "question": "Who was stoned by the people in Lystra?",
      "answer": "Paul. (Acts 14:19)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Governor Felix' wife by name __________ was a _________. Fill in the gaps.",
      "answer": "Drusilla, Jewess. Acts 24:24."
  },
  {
      "question": "Why was Paul still kept in prison by Felix, two years after his trial?",
      "answer": "Because Felix was hoping that Paul would offer him a bribe for his release and because he also want to grant the Jews a favour. Acts 24:26-27"
  },
  {
      "question": "Ananias, the high priest and the chief of the Jews met with Felix at Jerusalem to ask for a favour from him against Paul. What was the favour?",
      "answer": "That he should transfer Paul to Jerusalem in order to wait for him on the way and kill him. Acts 23:2-3."
  },
  {
      "question": "Fill in the gaps. Balak was the son of __________ and Balaam, the son of _________.",
      "answer": "Zippor, Beor. Joshua 24:9."
  },
  {
      "question": "How many men did Joshua send to spy the land of Jericho?",
      "answer": "Two (Joshua 2:1)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Complete this verse, Joshua17:14 _____________ spake unto Joshua, saying, Why hast thou given me but one lot and one portion to inherit, seeing I am a great people, forasmuch as the LORD hath blessed me hitherto?",
      "answer": "And the children of Joseph."
  },
  {
      "question": "According to Joshua 18:2, How many tribes were yet to receive their inheritance?",
      "answer": 7
  },
  {
      "question": "The Priesthood of the Lord is whose inheritance?",
      "answer": "The Levites. Joshua 18:7"
  },
  {
      "question": "______ and______ tribes were the second and fourth tribes that had their lot come out during the sharing of the inheritance according to Joshua 19:1,17",
      "answer": "Simeon and Issachar."
  },
  {
      "question": "In Acts 13, which city did Paul and Barnabas visit after leaving Paphos?",
      "answer": "After leaving Paphos, Paul and Barnabas visited the city of Perga in Pamphylia. (Acts 13:13)"
  },
  {
      "question": "When they decided to sail to Italy, Paul and some other prisoners were handed over to who?",
      "answer": "Julius, a centurion of Augustus’ band. Acts 27:1."
  },
  {
      "question": "Where did Joshua assemble the children of Israel, their elders and leaders to present themselves before God for a renewal of their covenant with Him?",
      "answer": "At Shechem. Joshua 24:1."
  },
  {
      "question": "Two important people came to see Festus during their visit to Caesarea. Mention their names?",
      "answer": "King Agrippa and Bernice. Acts 25:13."
  },
  {
      "question": "Paul and the other men in the ship stayed without food for how many days for fear of shipwreck?",
      "answer": "Fourteen (14) days. Acts 27:33."
  },
  {
      "question": "How many men went up to smite Ai the first time and how many men were killed?",
      "answer": "Joshua7: 4-5, About 3,000 men, 36 men were killed."
  },
  {
      "question": "When the Lord instructed Joshua on what to do to figure out the accursed man, what procedure did he give Joshua to follow?",
      "answer": "Joshua7:14, He was told to bring them according to their tribes, the chosen tribe shall then come according to their families, then the families according to their households, then the household shall come man by man."
  },
  {
      "question": "What did God instruct Joshua to do to the person with the accursed thing?",
      "answer": "Joshua7:15. He shall be burnt with fire, he and all that he hath."
  },
  {
      "question": "When Achan was taken and Joshua asked him to confess, what was his confession?",
      "answer": "Joshua7:21. He saw a goodly Babylonish garment, 200 shekels of silver, a wedge of Gold of 50 shekels weight and coveted them, took them and hid them in the earth in the midst of his tent and the silver under it."
  },
  {
      "question": "What was the name of the place where Achan and all he had was destroyed and what did the children of Israel do to him?",
      "answer": "Joshua7:24-26. The valley of Achor. All Israel stoned him with stones, burnt them with fire and raised a great heap of stones over them until this day."
  },
  {
      "question": "After Philip baptized the eunuch, The Spirit of the Lord caught away Philip and he was found where next?",
      "answer": "Acts8:40. Azotus."
  },
  {
      "question": "After leaving Perga in Pamphylia, where did Paul and his company go to?",
      "answer": "Antioch in Pisidia. (Acts 13:14)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Which city did Paul and Barnabas visit after leaving Antioch in Pisidia?",
      "answer": "Iconium (Acts 14:1)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Who did Paul heal in Lystra?",
      "answer": "A man who was crippled from birth (Acts 14:8)"
  },
  {
      "question": "What name did the people of Lystra call Paul and Barnabas?",
      "answer": "Paul was called Mercurius and Barnabas was called Jupiter. (Acts 14:12)"
  },
  {
      "question": "What did Joshua do to the Anakims?",
      "answer": "Joshua destroyed them utterly with their cities (Joshua 11:21)"
  },
  {
      "question": "How many kings did Joshua strike down as mentioned in Joshua 12?",
      "answer": "Joshua struck down a total of thirty-one kings. (Joshua 12:9-24)"
  },
  {
      "question": "What inheritance did the tribe of Levi receive?",
      "answer": "They did not receive any inheritance. The Lord God of Israel was their inheritance. (Joshua 13:33)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Who disturbed the land for an inheritance to the children of Israel in Joshua 14?",
      "answer": "Eleazar the priest, Joshua the son of Nun and the heads of the fathers of the tribes of the children of Israel. (Joshua 14:1)"
  },
  {
      "question": "What are the names of the children of Joseph?",
      "answer": "Manasseh and Ephraim (Joshua 14:4)"
  },
  {
      "question": "The Israelites did something the moment they began to wax strong according to Joshua 17:13",
      "answer": "They put the Canaanites to tribute."
  },
  {
      "question": "Quote Joshua 18:3?",
      "answer": "Joshua 18:3 And Joshua said unto the children of Israel, How long are ye slack to go to possess the land, which the LORD God of your fathers hath given you?"
  },
  {
      "question": "How many men from each tribe did Joshua requested for to go out to carry out the assignment of describing the land according to Joshua 18: 4?",
      "answer": "Three men from each tribe."
  },
  {
      "question": "__________, __________ and _________ tribes received their inheritance beyond Jordan on the East and by whom?",
      "answer": "Gad, Ruben and the half tribe of Manasseh and by Moses. Joshua 18:7."
  },
  {
      "question": "What city did Joshua cast lots for the children of Israel?",
      "answer": "Joshua 18:10. Shiloh."
  },
  {
      "question": "The cities allotted to the children of Gershon were from the tribes of ___________ , _______________, ______________, and half tribe of ______________ in Bashan. Fill in the gaps.",
      "answer": "Issachar, Asher, Naphtali and Half tribe of Manasseh in Bashan. Joshua 21:6"
  },
  {
      "question": "What was the name of the Governor Paul was taken to in Caesarea?",
      "answer": "Governor Felix. Acts 23:24."
  },
  {
      "question": "Governor Felix commanded that Paul should be temporarily kept under watch in ________ pending the hearing of his case.",
      "answer": "Herod’s judgement hall. Acts 23:35."
  },
  {
      "question": "What was the name of the first city allotted to the children of Aaron the priest? This city was also known as _________.",
      "answer": "Hebron. (A city of refuge for the slayer) Joshua 21:13."
  },
  {
      "question": "Whose son was Phinehas?",
      "answer": "Son of Eleazar the priest. Joshua 22:13."
  },
  {
      "question": "According to Acts 2:16, the day of Pentecost was previously for-told by ____________________",
      "answer": "Prophet Joel"
  },
  {
      "question": "Fill in the gap Acts19:3 And he said unto them, Unto what then were ye baptized? And they said, ___________",
      "answer": "Unto John's baptism"
  },
  {
      "question": "According to Acts 19:8, Paul was in the Synagogue for _________ months and was doing two major things",
      "answer": "Three months, disputing and persuading the things concerning the kingdom of God."
  },
  {
      "question": "Paul left the Synagogue in Acts 19:9 because?",
      "answer": "Majority of them were hardened and did not believe."
  },
  {
      "question": "Paul taught about Christ in a school of a certain man, what was his name?",
      "answer": "Tyrannus. Acts 19:9"
  },
  {
      "question": "According to Joshua 4:3, where in the Jordan did God command the men to take stones from?",
      "answer": "Where the Priests’ feet are standing"
  },
  {
      "question": "How many stone did the children of Israel take from Jordan to the camp to build a memorial?",
      "answer": "12 stones (Josh 4:3)"
  },
  {
      "question": "How many stones did Joshua set up at the middle of the Jordan?",
      "answer": "12 stones (Josh 4:9)"
  },
  {
      "question": "How many men equipped for war crossed to the plains of Jericho?",
      "answer": "40,000 (Josh 4:13)"
  },
  {
      "question": "At what instance did the waters of the Jordan come back together?",
      "answer": "When the Priest bearing the Ark set their foot on solid ground (Josh 4:18)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Quote Joshua 24:15.",
      "answer": "And if it seem evil unto you to serve the Lord, choose you this day whom ye will serve; whether the gods which your fathers served that were on the other side of the flood, or the gods of the Amorites, in whose land ye dwell: but as for me and my house, we will serve the Lord. Joshua 24:15."
  },
  {
      "question": "How many people accepted the message of Peter on the day of Pentecost?",
      "answer": "About 3000 (Acts 2:41)"
  },
  {
      "question": "What are the names of the 2 disciples that went up to the temple at the hour of prayers according to Acts 3:1",
      "answer": "Peter and John"
  },
  {
      "question": "After the healing of the lame at the Beautiful Gate, men gathered unto the disciples at _____________________",
      "answer": "Solomon’s Porch (Acts 3:11)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Nicolas, one of the men selected by the Apostles to wait on tables was from ________________",
      "answer": "Antioch (Acts 6:5)"
  },
  {
      "question": "An inheritance was given to Joshua, mention it.",
      "answer": "(Joshua 19:50) Timnath-serah"
  },
  {
      "question": "Who initiated that the children of Israel should appoint for themselves cities of refuge?",
      "answer": "God. Joshua 20:1-2"
  },
  {
      "question": "How many cities were appointed as cities of refuge?",
      "answer": "6. Joshua 20:7,8"
  },
  {
      "question": "_________ tribe had their boarder towards Jezreel?",
      "answer": "(Joshua 19:17,18) Issachar."
  },
  {
      "question": "_________ tribe had a large inheritance and had to share with _________.",
      "answer": "Joshua 19:9. The tribe of Judah shared their inheritance with the tribe of Simeon."
  },
  {
      "question": "How many souls (people) were in the ship altogether?",
      "answer": "Two hundred, three score and sixteen souls (276 people). Acts 27:37."
  },
  {
      "question": "What was the name and interpretation of the field in which Judas fell headlong?",
      "answer": "Aceldama, Field of blood (Acts1:19)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Quote Acts 1: 20",
      "answer": "For it is written in the book of Psalms: ‘Let his dwelling place be desolate, and let no one live in it; and let another take his office."
  },
  {
      "question": "Name the two men that were nominated to replace Judas Iscariot",
      "answer": "Joseph, called Barsabbas and Matthias (Acts 1:23)"
  },
  {
      "question": "What sat on the Apostles on the day of Pentecost?",
      "answer": "Divided tongues as of fire (Acts 2:3)"
  },
  {
      "question": "The second time Joshua was to go after Ai, who did he send away by night to lay an ambush for the city?",
      "answer": "Joshua8:3. 30,000 mighty men of valour."
  },
  {
      "question": "Where did those men who were to go at night and lay an ambush abide, answer it in full?",
      "answer": "Joshua8:9. They abode between Bethel and Ai, on the west side of Ai."
  },
  {
      "question": "What was the instruction God gave Joshua that was also a sign for those in ambush to rise quickly and take the city?",
      "answer": "Joshua8:18-19. “Stretch out the spear that is in thy hand toward Ai, for I will give it into thy hand”."
  },
  {
      "question": "What did God permit Joshua and the children of Israel to take as a spoil when they utterly destroyed the inhabitants of Ai?",
      "answer": "Joshua8:2&27. Only the cattle and the spoil of that city were they to take for a prey."
  },
  {
      "question": "The people of which city worked wilily and made themselves look like ambassadors to the Israelites?",
      "answer": "Joshua9:3-4. The people of Gibeon (The Gibeonites)."
  },
  {
      "question": "Stephen was accused of speaking blasphemous words against ______________________",
      "answer": "Moses and God (Acts 6:11)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Some set of people decided to imitate the miracles, signs and Wonders being wrought by the Holy Spirit through Apostle Paul, who were they and how did they learn their lesson?",
      "answer": "The seven sons of Sceva, the demons descended on them and dealt mercilessly with them."
  },
  {
      "question": "What was the worth of the books that were burnt in Acts 19:19.",
      "answer": "Fifty thousand pieces of silver."
  },
  {
      "question": "How long did Paul stayed in Greece?",
      "answer": "Acts 20:3 Three months."
  },
  {
      "question": "A certain man fell down from the third loft and died during Paul's long teaching, what was his name?",
      "answer": "Eutychus. Acts 20:9"
  },
  {
      "question": "Caleb was the son of who?",
      "answer": "Jephunneh. (Joshua 14:6, 14; 15:13)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Which tribe received Hebron as their inheritance?",
      "answer": "The tribe of Caleb received Hebron as their inheritance. (Joshua 14:13&14)"
  },
  {
      "question": "What was the name of Hebron before?",
      "answer": "The name of Hebron before was Kirjath-arba. (Joshua 14:15)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Which city did Caleb drive out the three sons of Anak from?",
      "answer": "Caleb drove out the three sons of Anak from the city of Hebron, as part of his inheritance in Joshua 15. (Joshua 15:13-14)"
  },
  {
      "question": "What are the names of the three sons of Anak?",
      "answer": "Sheshai, Ahiman and Talmai. (Joshua 15:14)"
  },
  {
      "question": "How did the disciples help Saul escape those who wanted to kill him at Damascus?",
      "answer": "Acts 9:25. Thw disciples took him by night and let him down by the wall in a basket."
  },
  {
      "question": "Why was Paul called Mercurius by the people of Lystra?",
      "answer": "He was called Mercurius because he was the chief speaker. (Acts 14:12)"
  },
  {
      "question": "What did the people of Lystra believe Paul and Barnabas to be?",
      "answer": "The people of Lystra believed that Paul and Barnabas were gods. (Acts 14:11)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Who stirred up the minds of the Gentiles in Lystra?",
      "answer": "The unbelieving Jews. (Acts 14:2)"
  },
  {
      "question": "What caused the contention between Paul and Barnabas causing them to depart from one another?",
      "answer": "The contention was about taking John Mark along on their journey. Barnabas wanted to bring him, but Paul disagreed. (Acts 15:38 & 39)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Who was Porcius Festus?",
      "answer": "He was Governor Felix’ successor. Acts 24:27."
  },
  {
      "question": "According to the book of Joshua, what chapters did Joshua bid farewell and admonished the people of Israel and their leaders?",
      "answer": "Joshua chapters 23 And 24"
  },
  {
      "question": "Therefore we said, “Let us now prepare to build us an altar, not for _________ nor for _________,” Fill in the gap. (Joshua 22:26)",
      "answer": "burnt offering nor for sacrifice. Joshua 22:26."
  },
  {
      "question": "The children of Reuben and the children of Gad called the altar ______________. Which means? ___________.",
      "answer": "Ed: Meaning:- For it shall be a witness between us that the Lord is God. Joshua 22:34."
  },
  {
      "question": "Who made this statement and to whom? “Be ye therefore very courageous to keep and to do all that is written in the book of the law of Moses, that ye turn not aside therefrom to the right hand or to the left. (Joshua 23:6)",
      "answer": "Joshua, To the Israelites, their elders, their heads, their Judges and their officers. Joshua 23:2;6."
  },
  {
      "question": "Quote Acts 5:29",
      "answer": "But Peter and the other apostles answered and said: “we ought to obey God rather than men…”"
  },
  {
      "question": "According to Acts 20:35, Apostle Paul quoted the exact words of Jesus in his address to the elders at Ephesus, what did he say?",
      "answer": "It is more blessed to give than to recieve."
  },
  {
      "question": "Caesarea was a city which of the evangelist lived according to Acts 21:8",
      "answer": "Phillip."
  },
  {
      "question": "Quote Acts21:9",
      "answer": "And the same man had four daughters, virgins, which did prophesy."
  },
  {
      "question": "_________ came from Judaea who took the girdle of Apostle Paul and bind his own feet and hands according to Acts 21:10.",
      "answer": "Agabus"
  },
  {
      "question": "Where did the people camp when they came up from the Jordan?",
      "answer": "Gilgal. (Josh 4:19)"
  },
  {
      "question": "What is the distance that the people were advised to keep from the Ark?",
      "answer": "1000 yards. (Josh 3:4)"
  },
  {
      "question": "The spies sent by Joshua stayed in the house of _____________________",
      "answer": "Rahab. (Josh 2:1)"
  },
  {
      "question": "How many days did the men that went to spy out Jericho hide in the hill country?",
      "answer": "3days. (Josh 2:16)"
  },
  {
      "question": "What is the name of the place where Joshua circumcised the Israelite men?",
      "answer": "Gibeath-haaraloth. (Josh 5:3)"
  },
  {
      "question": "The tribe of the children of _________ were the first to get their inheritance after Joshua casted the lot?",
      "answer": "Joshua 18:11. The tribe of the children of Benjamin."
  },
  {
      "question": "When Stephen was speaking before the council, how many people (his kindred) did he call for with his father Jacob?",
      "answer": "Acts7:14. Threescore and fifteen souls (75 souls)."
  },
  {
      "question": "In Stephen’s narration, how many months was Moses nourished in his father’s house before he was cast out?",
      "answer": "Acts7:20. Three months."
  },
  {
      "question": "When Stephen was full of the Holyghost and looked up steadfastly into heaven, what did he see?",
      "answer": "Acts7:55-56. He saw the heavens opened, saw the glory of God and Jesus (son of man) standing on the right hand of God."
  },
  {
      "question": "When they stoned Stephen what did he do?",
      "answer": "Acts7:59-60. He called upon God and said Lord Jesus, receive my Spirit, he kneeled down and cried with a loud voice, Lord, lay not this sin to their charge."
  },
  {
      "question": "According Joshua18:1 And the whole congregation of the children of Israel assembled together at ______ and set up the tabernacle of the congregation there. And the land was _______.",
      "answer": "Joshua 18:1 Shiloh, subdued before them."
  },
  {
      "question": "According to Joshua 17:1 Who was Joseph's first born?",
      "answer": "Manasseh."
  },
  {
      "question": "_________ was referred to as a man of war according to Joshua 17:1?",
      "answer": "Machir."
  },
  {
      "question": "According to Joshua 16:4, So the children of _______,_________and_______ took their inheritance.",
      "answer": "Joseph, Manasseh and Ephraim."
  },
  {
      "question": "Manasseh had ________ sons according to Joshua 17:1-2.",
      "answer": "7 sons."
  },
  {
      "question": "Who did Paul choose after the contention with Barnabas?",
      "answer": "Paul chose Silas. (Acts 15:40)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Fill in the gaps: “And ye went over Jordan and came unto Jericho: and the men of Jericho fought against you, the _________, and the _________, and the _________, and the _________, and the _________, the _________, and the _________; and I delivered them into your hand.",
      "answer": "Amorites, Perizzites, Canaanites, Hittites, Girgashites, Hivites, and the Jebusites. Joshua 24:11."
  },
  {
      "question": "Who was the father of Abraham and Nahor?",
      "answer": "Terah. Joshua 24:2."
  },
  {
      "question": "After eating enough, Paul and the men in the ship casted out the wheat into the sea. Why?",
      "answer": "They did this to lighten the ship. Acts 27:38."
  },
  {
      "question": "When part of the ship was broken to pieces, the soldiers planned to kill the prisoners to prevent them from swimming to escape, but the centurion gave an order to counter their plan in order to save Paul’s life. What was the order? Acts 27:43-44",
      "answer": "He commanded that those who can swim should cast themselves first into the sea, and get to land. While the rest should cross with; some on board (planks), some on broken pieces of the ship. And they all landed safely. Acts 27:43-44."
  },
  {
      "question": "What was the mistake Joshua and the Princes of the congregation made with the Gibeonites?",
      "answer": "Joshua 9:14-15. They took of their victuals and asked not counsel at the mouth of the Lord before making peace with them and made a league with them to let them live and the princes of the congregation sware unto them."
  },
  {
      "question": "When Joshua and the princes realized that they have been beguiled, what did Joshua say to them?",
      "answer": "Joshua 9:22-23. Joshua said they are cursed and none of them shall be free from being bondmen and hewers of wood and drawers of water for the house of God."
  },
  {
      "question": "Mention the names of the cities that were involved in the deceit against Joshua and the Israelites.",
      "answer": "Joshua 9:17. Gibeon, Chephirah, Beeroth and Kirjathjearim."
  },
  {
      "question": "Adonizedec king of Jerusalem sent unto four other kings asking for their help to fight Gibeon for making peace with Israel, Mention the name of the four other kings and their cities.",
      "answer": "Joshua 10:3. Hoham king of Hebron, Piram king of Jarmuth, Japhia king of Lachish and unto Debir King of Eglon."
  },
  {
      "question": "What did Joshua command the sun and the moon to do while fighting against the five kings that came to fight the Gibeonites and it happened for how long?",
      "answer": "Joshua 10:12-13. Joshua commanded the Sun to stand still in Gibeon and the moon in the valley of Ajalon, they hasted not to go down about a whole day."
  },
  {
      "question": "When Peter went to the housetop to pray and fell into a trance, he saw the heaven opened and a certain vessel descending unto him, what were the 4 things in the vessel?",
      "answer": "Acts 10:12. All manner of four footed beasts of the earth, and wild beast and creeping things and fowl of the air."
  },
  {
      "question": "In Acts 16, Paul received a vision from who and what was the vision?",
      "answer": "Paul received a vision from a man of Macedonia. The vision was asking him to come to Macedonia and help them. (Acts 16:9)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Where did Paul receive the vision from the Macedonian man?",
      "answer": "In Troas (Acts 16:8 & 9)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Who was the seller of purple whom Paul encountered and baptized?",
      "answer": "Lydia. (Acts 16:14)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Who was the certain damsel that followed Paul and Silas for many days?",
      "answer": "She was a girl possessed with a spirit of divination who brought her masters gain by soothsaying. (Acts 16:16)"
  },
  {
      "question": "What was Kiriath-Sepher’s previous name?",
      "answer": "Debir. (Joshua 15:15)"
  },
  {
      "question": "What was the name of Caleb's daughter that he gave to the man who smote Kiriath-Sepher? ",
      "answer": "Achsah. (Joshua 15:16)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Who was Othniel?",
      "answer": "He was the son of Kenaz, brother of Caleb. (Joshua 15:17)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Who smote (killed) Kiriath-Sepher?",
      "answer": "Othniel. (Joshua 15:17)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Who did the children of Judah fail to drive out from the Jerusalem?",
      "answer": "Jebusites the inhabitants of Jerusalem. (Joshua 15:63)"
  },
  {
      "question": "What was the name of the Island Paul and other people in the ship landed safely at?",
      "answer": "Malta. Acts 28:1."
  },
  {
      "question": "Quote Acts 4:11",
      "answer": "This is the stone which was rejected by you builders, but has become the chief cornerstone."
  },
  {
      "question": "How old was the man that was healed at the Beautiful Gate?",
      "answer": "Over 40yrs (Acts 5:22)"
  },
  {
      "question": "What is the meaning of the name Barnabas?",
      "answer": "Son of Consolation (Acts 5:36)"
  },
  {
      "question": "How many hours interval was there between the deaths of Ananias and Sapphira his wife?",
      "answer": "About 3hrs (Acts 5:7)"
  },
  {
      "question": "How old was Joshua when he died?",
      "answer": "At the age of 110 years. Joshua 24:29"
  },
  {
      "question": "The grievous complaints laid against Paul by the Jews before Festus could not be proved. True or False.?",
      "answer": "True. Acts 23:7"
  },
  {
      "question": "Quote Joshua 23:8.",
      "answer": "But cleave unto the Lord your God as you have done unto this day. Joshua 23:8."
  },
  {
      "question": "Why was Joshua bidding farewell and admonishing the Israelites?",
      "answer": "Because he was old and stricken in age. Joshua 23:2"
  },
  {
      "question": "Quote Acts 23:11.",
      "answer": "And the night following, the Lord stood by him, and said, “Be of good cheer Paul; for as thou hast testified of me in Jerusalem, so must thou bear witness also at Rome.” Acts 23:11."
  },
  {
      "question": "Why did Apostle Paul made this statement, \"What mean ye to weep and to break mine heart? for I am ready not to be bound only, but also to die at Jerusalem for the name of the Lord Jesus\".",
      "answer": "He was being persuaded not to go the Jerusalem because of the persecution that awaited him there. Acts 21:12"
  },
  {
      "question": "When Peter came to Lydda, he found a certain man named _________ which had kept his bed ___________ years and was sick of the ___________.",
      "answer": "Acts 9:33. Aeneas, eight, palsy."
  },
  {
      "question": "Fill in the gaps; Now, there was at _________, a certain disciple named __________ which by interpretation is called __________.",
      "answer": "Acts 9:36. Joppa, Tabitha, Dorcas."
  },
  {
      "question": "Who did Peter tarry with while he was at Joppa?",
      "answer": "Acts 9:43. He tarried with one Simon a tanner at Joppa."
  },
  {
      "question": "Fill in the gaps: There was a certain man in _____________ called ________, a centurion of the band called the __________ band, a __________ man and one that feared God with all his house.",
      "answer": "Acts 10:1-2. Caesarea, Cornelius, Italian, devout."
  },
  {
      "question": "According to Act 1:3, how many days did Jesus appear unto the disciples after resurrection?",
      "answer": "40 days"
  },
  {
      "question": "Jesus asked the disciples to tarry in _______________ and wait for the __________________ of the father.",
      "answer": "Jerusalem, Promise (Acts 1:4)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Quote Acts 1:8",
      "answer": "But you shall receive power when the Holy Spirit has come upon you; and you shall be witnesses to me in Jerusalem, and in all Judea and Samaria and to the end of the earth."
  },
  {
      "question": "At what mountain did Jesus ascend to heaven?",
      "answer": "Olivet (Acts 1: 12)"
  },
  {
      "question": "How many people alltogether went to the upper room?",
      "answer": "About 120. Acts1:15."
  },
  {
      "question": "Why were Paul and Silas thrown into prison?",
      "answer": "They were thrown into prison because the masters of the girl saw that the hope of their gains were gone as she was healed and accused them of causing disturbance in the city and teaching customs which are not lawful. (Acts 16:19 - 21)."
  },
  {
      "question": "Joshua was buried in the border of his inheritance at _____?",
      "answer": "Timnath-Serah, which is in mount Ephraim, on the north side of the hill of Gaash. Joshua 24:30."
  },
  {
      "question": "Acts 28:28 states expressly that salvation of God is sent unto the ____________ and they will hear it.",
      "answer": "Gentiles. Acts 28:28."
  },
  {
      "question": "According to the book of Joshua, who was sent for to place a curse on the Israelites but ended up Blessing them?",
      "answer": "Balaam. Joshua 24:9-10."
  },
  {
      "question": "What verse of Joshua 24 referred to God as a jealous God?",
      "answer": "Joshua 24:19."
  },
  {
      "question": "Paul was on his way to __________ when he had a divine encounter with the Lord Jesus Christ?",
      "answer": "Damascus. Acts 26:12-15."
  },
  {
      "question": "Mention at least two of Paul's companion according to Acts 21:4",
      "answer": "Acts20:4 And there accompanied him into Asia, Sopater of Berea; and of the Thessalonians, Aristarchus and Secundus; and Gaius of Derbe, and Timotheus; and of Asia, Tychicus and Trophimus."
  },
  {
      "question": "What did Paul refer the Baptism of John to be?",
      "answer": "The baptism of Repentance Acts 19:4"
  },
  {
      "question": "Quote Acts 19:20",
      "answer": "Acts19:20 So mightily grew the word of God and prevailed."
  },
  {
      "question": "Who did Herod the king kill and why did he proceed further to take Peter also?",
      "answer": "Acts12:2-3. James the brother of John, because he saw that it pleased the Jews."
  },
  {
      "question": "The chief of the Island whose name was ____________ cautiously received and lodged Paul and others for _________ days. Fill in the gaps.",
      "answer": "Publius, Three (3). Acts 28:7."
  },
  {
      "question": "__________ was referred to as an old disciple in Acts 21:16",
      "answer": "Mnason of Cyprus"
  },
  {
      "question": "Complete this verse, Acts 22:7 And I fell unto the ground, and heard a voice saying unto me, Saul, Saul, ________",
      "answer": "Why persecutest thou me?"
  },
  {
      "question": "According to Acts 22:10a, Paul's statement revealed ________.",
      "answer": "Total submission and willingness to follow the command of the Lord."
  },
  {
      "question": "Complete this verse, Acts 22:15 “For thou shalt be his witness unto all men of what thou hast _______&__________”.",
      "answer": "Seen and heard."
  },
  {
      "question": "When the angel of the Lord released Peter from prison, where did Peter go and what were they doing there?",
      "answer": "Acts12:12. The house of Mary the mother of John whose surname was Mark, where many were gathered praying."
  },
  {
      "question": "Who knew/recognized Peter’s voice as he knocked at the door of the gate and what did she do?",
      "answer": "Acts12:13-15. Rhoda, she opened not the gate for gladness, but ran in and told them that Peter stood before the gate, they said she was mad, but she affirmed that it was Peter."
  },
  {
      "question": "Who did the angel of the Lord smite after making an oration, why was he smitten and what happened to him?",
      "answer": "Acts12:21-23. King Herod, because he gave not God the glory when the people shouted that it was the voice of a god and not of a man, he was eaten of worms and gave up the ghost."
  },
  {
      "question": "Who did Barnabas and Saul take with them when they returned from Jerusalem and had fulfilled their ministry?",
      "answer": "Acts12:25. John whose surname was Mark."
  },
  {
      "question": "In which city were some Jews envious of Paul and Silas?",
      "answer": "Thessalonica (Acts 17:1,5)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Paul and his company left Tyre to ______ city?",
      "answer": "Ptolemias. Acts 21:7"
  },
  {
      "question": "When Peter refused to eat what was in the vessel, the voice spoke to him the second time and said what?",
      "answer": "Acts10:15. What God hath cleansed, that call not thou common."
  },
  {
      "question": "While Peter was preaching to Cornelius and those who were with him, what happened?",
      "answer": "Acts10:44. The Holy ghost fell on all of them which heard the word."
  },
  {
      "question": "The apostles and brethren that were in Judaea heard that the gentiles had also received the word and when Peter was come up to Jerusalem, who contended with him?",
      "answer": "Acts 11:2. They that were of the circumcision contended with him."
  },
  {
      "question": "After Peter finished narrating the event to the apostles and the brethren, when they heard those things, what did they do?",
      "answer": "Acts11:18. They held their peace and glorified God saying “Then hath God also to the gentiles granted repentance unto life”."
  },
  {
      "question": "What were the names of the two people who believed in Paul's message in Areopagus?",
      "answer": "Dionysius the Areopagite and a woman named Damaris (Acts 17:34)"
  },
  {
      "question": "Who was Eleazar's father?",
      "answer": "Aaron. Joshua 24:33."
  },
  {
      "question": "What was Joshua referring to as strange gods?",
      "answer": "Any other god apart from the true living God. (Engaging in idolatry) Joshua 24:20."
  },
  {
      "question": "Who felt it was unreasonable to send Paul (a prisoner) to Rome, and yet unable to specify the crimes laid against him.” Who did he share his opinion with?",
      "answer": "Festus, king Agrippa. Acts 25:27."
  },
  {
      "question": "Publius father was sick in bed. He was down with __________ and __________, but Paul prayed for him and he was healed. Fill in the gaps.",
      "answer": "Fever and Bloody flux (Dysentery). Acts 28:8."
  },
  {
      "question": "How long did Barnabas and Saul stay in Antioch?",
      "answer": "Acts11:26. A whole year."
  },
  {
      "question": "Whose house did Paul and Silas enter when they left the prison keepers’ house?",
      "answer": "They entered the house of Lydia. (ANS: 16:40)"
  },
  {
      "question": "What event made the keeper of the prison believe in God?",
      "answer": "The earthquake that shook the foundations of the prison, causing all the doors to open and the prisoners' bands to be loosened. (Acts 16:26,34)"
  },
  {
      "question": "What response did Paul and Silas’ give to the prison keeper when he asked what he must do to be saved?",
      "answer": "And they said, Believe on the Lord Jesus Christ, and thou shalt be saved and thy house. (Acts 16:31)"
  },
  {
      "question": "What was the name of the disciple that Paul met in Lystra whose mother was a Jew and his father was Greek?",
      "answer": "Timotheus (Acts 16:1)"
  },
  {
      "question": "According to Acts 28:31; Paul preached about the kingdom of God and taught people about the Lord Jesus Christ with all confidence and no restriction (no man forbidding him). True or False?",
      "answer": "True. Acts 28:31."
  }
]